(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.1",
"generated_at": "2026-06-20T00:23:55.036811",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
鷹嶺ルイ 生誕LIVE - Luminous Stairs -
Takane Lui Birthday Live - Luminous Stairs -
3D新衣装お披露目
[3D New Outfit Reveal]
超重大告知あり
[Super Major Announcement Included!]
3D新衣装お披露目 / 超重大発表 / 告知あり
[3D New Outfit Reveal / Super Important Announcement / Announcement Included]
GUEST 01: AZKi / GUEST 02: 猫又おかゆ
GUEST 01: AZKi / GUEST 02: Nekomata Okayu
GUEST 03: 常闇トワ / GUEST 04: 森カリオペ
GUEST 03: Tokoyami Towa / GUEST 04: Mori Calliope
GUEST 05: ハコス・ベールズ / GUEST 06: IRyS
GUEST 05: Hakos Baelz / GUEST 06: IRyS
GUEST 07: ラプラス・ダークネス / GUEST 08: 博衣こより
GUEST 07: Laplus Darknesss / GUEST 08: Hakui Koyori
GUEST 09: 尾丸ポルカ / GUEST 10: 虎金妃笑虎
GUEST 09: Omaru Polka / GUEST 10: Kogane Mikoto
GUEST 11: フワワ・アビスガード / GUEST 12: モココ・アビスガード
GUEST 11: Fuwawa Abyssgard / GUEST 12: Mococo Abyssgard
GUEST 13: 輪堂千代 / GUEST 14: 風真いろは
GUEST 13: Rinndo Chiyo / GUEST 14: Kazama Iroha
走りなさい 早く もっと 早く
Run, run, faster, even faster,
哀しみに 追いつかれないように
so you don't get caught by sorrow.
探しなさい 明かりの灯る道を
Search, search for the path where the light shines,
それは それは 眩いでしょう
it must be, it must be dazzling.
挑みなさい 君の美しさや 尊さを
Challenge, challenge...
傷つけるモノに
...the things that hurt your beauty and preciousness.
眠りなさい 疲れたら 眠りなさい
Sleep, sleep when you get tired,
神話を持たない あの星座のように
like that constellation that has no myth.
手を離した後 君は気づくだろう
After letting go of your hand, you'll probably notice,
指の形 体温
the shape of your fingers, the warmth.
その名残が 胸を刺す
That lingering memory stabs my chest.
忘れたことも 忘れてしまえ
Forget what you've forgotten,
哀しみも 温もりも 消えてしまえ
let the sorrow and warmth disappear too.
されど今も 耳に残るは
Yet, what still remains in my ears even now...
...咲いた祝いを 願うような サヨナラ
...like a farewell that wishes for a blooming celebration.
Ah do ah do... Love you and you
踊りなさい 誰に笑われても
Dance, even if everyone laughs at you.
淡い雪を払う エチュードのように
Like an etude brushing off the light snow,
叫びなさい 底から叫びなさい
scream, scream from the depths of your heart.
ここにいて確かにいたんだと響かせて保存
Let it echo that you were indeed here.
行き逢いの空に 遠花火が滲む
In the passing sky, distant fireworks blur.
帰るべき家を探す
Searching for a home to return to,
長い長い旅路を行くなら
if you are to embark on a long, long journey...
高らかに鳴らせ その心臓は
Ring it out loud, that heart of yours
最後の一打まで君のものだ
is yours until the very last beat.
涙 涙 溢れるがいい
Tears, tears, let them overflow.
この足跡が 君の周りをも 育てただろう
These footprints must have nurtured even your surroundings too.
それは千年の ホームシックでした
That was a thousand years of homesickness,
無限さえも 数え終えて
having finished counting even infinity.
怪獣のような 世界の隅っこで
In the corner of a monster-like world,
戦い続ける人 君はエルス、エルス
a person who keeps fighting, you are Erthe, Erthe.
旅は続く
The journey continues.
忘れたことも 忘れてしまえ
Forget even the things you've forgotten.
悲しみも 温もりも 消えてしまえ
Let both the sadness and the warmth disappear.
今を 今を 生き抜く言葉
The words to survive the present, the present.
硬く咲いた祝いを 願うような サヨナラ
A farewell, as if wishing for a firmly blooming celebration.
Ah do ah do... Love you and you...
Ah do ah do...
IRIS OUT
[Title: IRIS OUT]
溜め溜め溜めの 脳みその中から やめろ馬鹿と喚くモラリティ
From inside my brain that's storing, morality screams 'stop it, you idiot'
ダーリンベイビーダーリン 半端なくラブと煌めき 浮き足立つフィロソフィー
Darling baby darling, an extraordinary love and sparkle, a nervous philosophy
死ぬほど可愛い 上目遣い
A deadly cute upward glance,
何か司法に触れる具合
something like violating the law.
ばら撒く安心 気付けば当人 この世に生まれて君が悪い
Scattering peace of mind, before you know it, you're at fault for being born
やたらと しんどい 恋煩い バラバラになる頭とこの身体
Incredibly painful lovesickness, my head and this body fall apart
けど脈からアイラヴが吹き出て
But I-Love bursts from my pulse,
IRIS OUT
痛いどうしよう
It hurts, what should I do?
この思いをどうしよう
What should I do with this feeling?
アバラの奥のザラメが 溶けてゲロになりそう
The brown sugar deep in my ribs is melting and about to become vomit.
東狂 街灯で溺れ死にそう
East-mad, about to drown in the streetlights,
今この世で君だけ大正解
right now in this world, only you are the absolute correct answer.
ダーリン ダーリン...
Darling, darling...
ひっくり返っても勝ちようない 君だけルール適用外
Even if things turn upside down, there's no way to win, you're exempt from the rules.
4つとも押せるは黒しかない 喝上げ放題
There's only black to press on all four, all-you-can-extort.
君が笑顔で放ったおどけたタブレット 鉄骨にシグマ 申し訳ないな
The playful tablet you released with a smile, sigma on the steel frame, I'm so sorry.
嫌を指して 貫いて
Point to your dislikes, pierce through.
ここ弱点？
Is this the weak spot?
死ぬほど可愛い 上目遣い
A deadly cute upward glance,
何か司法に触れる具合
something like violating the law.
ばら撒く安心 気付けば当人
Scattering peace of mind, before you know it, you're the one at fault
この世に生まれて君が悪い
for being born in this world.
バチモンでもいい何でもいい 今君と懐いてる 全て欲しい
Even a knockoff is fine, anything is fine, I want everything attached to you.
けど脈からアイラヴが吹き出て
But I-Love bursts from my pulse,
IRIS OUT
痛いどうしよう
It hurts, what should I do?
この思いをどうしよう
What should I do with this feeling?
アバラの奥 of ザラメが 溶けてゲロになりそう
The brown sugar deep in my ribs is melting and about to become vomit.
東狂 街灯で溺れ死にそう
East-mad, about to drown in the streetlights...
目をバチ開いて踊るワン・ツー・スリー
Open your eyes wide and dance, one, two, three...
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now in this world, only you are the absolute answer!
ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン...
Darling, Darling, Darling, Darling...
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity,
答えを示す時だ
it is time to show you the answer.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先へ
To the end of the spiral leading to the illusion...
言い訳に聞こえた理由は
The reason it sounded like an excuse
儚い未来 手繰った弱さ
is the weakness that reeled in a fleeting future.
それを強さとはき違えている
You are mistaking that for strength.
憎い、憎い 醜い、醜い
Hateful, hateful, ugly, ugly,
月を隠すほどの
enough to hide the moon.
黒く、黒く 淀む、心
Black, black, a murky heart...
君さえ居なければ
If only you weren't here!
ゆらいでいる ゆらいでる 花のように意思を繋ぐ
Swaying, swaying, connecting our wills like a flower.
奪っていく 奪っていく 嵐のように心を裂く
Taking away, taking away, tearing the heart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity, it is time to show you the answer.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先に
At the end of the spiral leading to the illusion,
待つのは誰
who is waiting?
生まれ落ちた運命を飲んだ
I swallowed the fate I was born into,
背負った数の名前を覚えた
and remembered the names of all the burdens I carry.
爛れるほど 心燃やす感情
An emotion that burns my heart to a crisp.
憎い、憎い 醜い、醜い
Hateful, hateful, ugly, ugly,
世界を分かつほどの
enough to divide the world.
怒り、怒り 燃やす、心
Anger, anger, this burning heart...
君さえ居なければ
If only you weren't here!
ゆらいでいる ゆらいでる 花のように意思を繋ぐ
Swaying, swaying, connecting our wills like a flower.
奪っていく 奪っていく 嵐のように心を裂く
Taking away, taking away, tearing the heart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity, it is time to show you the answer.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先で
At the end of the spiral leading to the illusion...
鬼哭に耳を傾けた仕舞よ
Listen to the demon's cry, for it is the end.
この身に宿る万物で終いよ
Ending with everything that dwells in this body.
夢幻を他者に託した弱き人
A weak person who entrusted the illusion to others.
命の輝きは幾星霜に
The radiance of life over countless years...
祈りの瞬きが照らす斜陽に
In the twilight illuminated by the flicker of prayers...
千夜を身に宿し
Carrying thousands of nights within...
解を押し付ける
Forcing an answer upon you.
枯らしていく 枯らしていく 夢幻の夜に花を咲く
Withering, withering, blooming flowers in the illusionary night.
繋いでいく 繋いでいく
Connecting, connecting...
嵐に種を撒いていく
Scattering seeds in the storm.
ゆらいでいる ゆらいでる 花のように意思を繋ぐ
Swaying, swaying, connecting our wills like a flower.
奪っていく 奪っていく 嵐のように心を裂く
Taking away, taking away, tearing the heart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity, it is time to show you the answer.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先で
At the end of the spiral leading to the illusion...
待つのは誰
who is waiting?
イェーイ！ はーい！
Yeah! Hi!
ということでニコに来ていただきました！
And so, we have Nico here with us today!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！ニコたんです！
Happy Birthday! It's Nico-tan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
よくお歌い... 歌い切れたな！
We really managed to... sing it all the way through!
なんかもうね、顔、顔はもう、涙...
Seriously, my face... I'm already in tears...
涙で滲んでいる！
My eyes are blurring with tears!
「大丈夫か？」って。
Asking me, "Are you okay?"
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いやいやいや、ありがとうございます、こちらこそ。
No, no, thank you so much, the pleasure is mine.
ということで、2024年の生誕祭はですね、あの、ニコさんが生出演ということで。
So, for my 2024 Birthday Celebration, Niko-san is here as a live guest.
はい！
Yes!
あの、ニコたんも3Dになったということで。
Niko-tan also got her 3D model.
はい！
Yes!
で、ニコたんが「いつかルイ先輩の隣で歌いたい」って言ってくれてたんで。
And since Niko-tan told me she wanted to sing by my side one day...
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
なので今日は、お呼びさせていただきました。
So I invited her here today.
ありがとうございます、本当に！
Thank you so much, truly!
いや、めちゃくちゃ格好良い曲を歌っていただきましたが、皆さんいかがでしたか？
We sang an incredibly cool song together. Everyone, how did you like it?
いや、本当に嬉しかったです。
I was really so happy.
「ニコたん良かったね」って。
Everyone is saying, "I'm so glad for you, Niko-tan."
いや、良いです、もうニコたんのことは良いです！
No, it's fine! Stop talking about me!
「ニコたん良かったね」って。
"I'm so glad for you, Niko-tan."
いや、そんなことよりですよ、ルイ先輩、ニコたん何回も...
More importantly, Lui-senpai...
今日、重大告知もあるし。
You also have a major announcement today.
そうなんです。
That's right.
新衣装もあるし。
And a new outfit too.
新衣装もあるんです。なので...
I have a new outfit too. So...
出るんでしたっけ？
Are you going to show it?
これね、たくさんね、ここのハッシュタグ「#鷹嶺ルイ超重大生誕LIVE」ってありますので、
Yes, so please post a lot using the hashtag "#鷹嶺ルイ超重大生誕LIVE" on screen.
それでたくさんたくさん、もうポストしてくれたら嬉しいなと思うんですけど。
I'd be so happy if you posted a whole lot.
今日はたくさん告知もありますし。
Since we have many announcements today.
そうですよね！
Right!
いや、ニコたん気になるのは、もちろん重大告知のでっかさも気になるんですけど、
Of course I'm curious about how huge the major announcement is,
新衣装がやっぱりね、気になる。
but I'm really curious about the new outfit.
やっぱルイ先輩といえば、こう、ちょっとダークネスな感じなのかなとか思ったり。
Since it's you, Lui-senpai, I thought it might be a bit dark.
黒、黒系なのかな、みたいな。
Like, all black or something.
ああ、なるほど、なるほど、なるほど。
Ah, I see, I see, I see.
そう思いますよね？
Everyone thinks so, right?
まあ、それもあります！
Well, that's part of it!
おお！ それも？
Oh! That too?
はい！
Yes!
ということは？
Which means...?
最初ね、あの、固定でも書かせていただいたんですけど、
As I wrote in the pinned message,
あの、新衣装は最初、サブカラー...
the new outfit is first shown in its sub-color...
へっ？！
What?!
...で、ちょっと清楚な感じの衣装になっております。
...and it's a slightly pure-looking outfit.
え、それもある？ 他にもあるってこと？
Wait, that too? Does that mean there's more?
はい！ めちゃくちゃ大量にサブを用意しておりますので、
Yes! I've prepared a massive amount of sub-variations,
最後までね、楽しんで...
so please enjoy it until the very end...
なんか、なんかすごい騒いでる。
Wow, everyone is going wild in chat.
おかしい！ サブも？
That's crazy! Even sub-variations?
まあ、いいや！ 今日は来てくれてありがとう。
Anyway! Thank you for coming today.
あ、わかりました！ ニコたんも楽屋で応援してます！ それでは...
Ah, I see! I'll be cheering you on from the dressing room! Well then...
あ、違います、違います、そちらは舞踏会会場なんで。
Ah, no, no, that way is the ballroom.
こっちダメなんですか、ニコたん？
Can't I go this way?
はい、ニコたんは呼んでない。招待状もらってないでしょ？
Yes, you're not invited there. You didn't get an invitation, right?
もらってないけど...
I didn't, but...
もらってないけど、じゃあ、すいませんが楽屋の方に、あちらから。
You didn't. So please head to the dressing room that way.
いやあああ！
Noooo!
はい、スタッフお願いします！
Staff, please take her!
ルイ先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Lui-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとう、ありがとう！
Thank you, thank you!
大好きです！
I love you!
ありがとう、チューはしないけど。
Thank you, though I won't kiss you.
頑張ってください！
Do your best!
ありがとう、ありがとうね！ ありがとうね！
Thank you, thank you so much!
ということでニコたんに来ていただきました。
And that was our guest, Niko-tan.
はい、えー新衣装もね、たくさん見せていきますので、最後まで楽しんでいただけたらなと思います。
Yes, I'll be showing off many versions of my new outfit, so please stay tuned until the end.
楽屋のニコたんも楽しんでくださいね！
Enjoy the show from the dressing room, Niko-tan!
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
「ZIG-ZAG」
"ZIG-ZAG"
One, two, three, four.
小線だって囁いた　問いが　ラッタ　タラッタ
The question whispered as if it were a minor line, ratta-taratta
こびり憑いて　離れんわ　駄目だ　ラッタ　タラッタ
It clings and won't leave, it's no use, ratta-taratta
有象無象の生活像が　思いつかないや
I can't imagine a lifestyle of the rabble
忘れたいから　歌った　馬鹿だ　ラッタ　タラッタ
I sang because I wanted to forget, I'm a fool, ratta-taratta
恨むことも　憎むことも
Both begrudging and hating
賢くない　故　出来なかった
I couldn't do, because I'm not smart
これがキミの　結末ならば
If this is your ending
笑って　しまいたい
I want to laugh it off
ほど　うそ　うそ　うそ
to the point of lie, lie, lie...
うそつき
Liar
やだ　大　大　大　大な　奇跡
No, a grand, grand, grand, grand miracle
とか　ちょっと　覗んちゃって
or something, I ended up wishing for it a bit
抱きしめて
Embrace me...
壊すけどいいの？
Even if I destroy you, is that okay?
囚われたい私の
Of me, who wants to be imprisoned...
デス デス デデ デス！
Death, death, de-de-death!
夢の中で君と手を繋いでいるの
In my dreams, I am holding hands with you...
何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
...just as we were back then, when we knew nothing.
でも分かっているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know that I will wake up soon.
それならいっそ 君の手をそっと 閉じ込めさせて
In that case, let me gently lock your hand away.
ほら
Look!
今 今 今
Right now, now, now!
奪いたい痛いな
I want to steal you away so much, it hurts.
奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃってもいいやいやいやいや
It's fine even if I wish for a bit of a miracle.
タチが悪いわ
How malicious.
冷めない冷めない冷めない
I won't wake up, won't wake up, won't wake up!
おかしなとこ全部えぐり取って
Gouge out all the strange parts.
薄情だって結構 好きに呼んでいいよ Sung
If you call me heartless, that's fine too. Call me whatever you like.
醒める前にバイバイしたいの
I want to say goodbye before I wake up.
デス デス デデ デス デス デス デデ デス！
Death, death, de-de-death! Death, death, de-de-death!
世界欺く揺るぎない正義
The unwavering justice that deceives this world...
ほどいて真実この手の中
...I'll unravel the truth, into these hands.
アイのシナリオ
[Ai no Scenario]
大胆不敵な影が華麗に踊る
An audacious shadow dances elegantly.
君が隠してる秘密いつか聞かせてよ
Tell me someday about the secret you're hiding.
伸ばした手で触れる事は誰にもできない
No one can touch it with their outstretched hand...
君が隠してる世界僕に見させてよ
...so let me see the world you're hiding.
揺れる難解な心
A troubled, wavering heart...
解き明かして奪うその瞳
...I'll dispel it and steal away those eyes.
不安がって泣いてたって 見つけらんないよ
Even if you cry in fear, you won't find it.
狙う真実は
The truth I was aiming for...
どこへ消えた
...where did it vanish to?
たとえ世界欺く解答だとしても Mom
Even if it were an answer that deceives the world...
「信じて」差し出す掌
...trust me and reach out your hand.
決して逃げない怖くはないから
I'll never run away, because I'm not scared.
目を開け弱さをかき消すんだ
I'll open my eyes and drown out my weakness!
繰り返される運命に君は気づいてる？
Are you beginning to realize how repetitive this fate is?
僕が隠してる秘密いつか聞かせるよ
Someday I'll tell you the secret I'm hiding.
歩み寄る偽りの影君は知らない
A deceptive shadow is approaching, but you don't know.
芽生えた記憶は絡む必然の棘で
Budding memories are entangled by thorns of inevitability.
守りたい想いで
With just the desire to protect...
ただ立ち向かって解くその絆
...I'll take a stand and unravel this bond!
何度だって助けるって揺るぎはしないよ
I'll save you as many times as it takes; I'll never waver!
隠す真実は
The hidden truth...
どこへ消えた
...where did it vanish to?
たとえ世界を敵に回したとしても
Even if you make an enemy of the entire world...
信じて僕だけ未来も
...believe only in me and the future!
決して逃げない迷いはないから
I'll never run away, because there's no doubt in me.
シナリオ壊して抗うんだ
I'll break the scenario and fight back!
世界を敵に回したとしても
Even if I make the world my enemy,
「信じて」差し出す掌
"Believe me," I reach out my palm
決して離さない 想いは届いた
I will never let go, my feelings have reached you
結んだ運命 この手の中
The connected destiny is in my hands
繰り返された...
Even if it is a repeated...
解答だとしても
...answer,
決して逃げない
I will never run away,
怖くはないから
because I'm not afraid,
抗うんだ
I will resist.
何度も！何度も！走り続けるよ！
Again and again! Again and again! We will keep on running!
Wake up! 新星！
Wake up! Rising star!
Shift up! ギア回して！
Shift up! Turn the gear!
Speed up! ハート吐いて！
Speed up! Let your heartbeat out!
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
Jump up! てっぺんへ！
Jump up! To the top!
Turn up! 声合わせて！
Turn up! Match our voices!
Dream up! 未来繋いで！
Dream up! Connecting the future!
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
最高潮コンディション 調子ガンガン上がってこう
Peak condition, let's keep on rising!
栄光のチャンピオン 虎視眈々と狙ってこう
The glorious champion, let's aim for it vigilantly!
ハイペース！ / マイペース！
High pace! / My pace!
気合レース！ / 猛集中！
Spirited race! / Fierce concentration!
駆ける旋風は限界突破 ハートに限界ない
Running whirlwind is the limit, there's no limit to our hearts
U.M.A. Let's go!
最高潮パッション ぶつかり合えばガチ勝負
Peak passion, if we clash it's a real fight!
千載一遇のチャンスを 全力出して掴んでこう
Grab this once-in-a-lifetime chance with all your might!
ハイペース！ / ハイペース！
High pace! / High pace!
気合レース！ / 猛集中！
Spirited race! / Fierce concentration!
駆ける想いは絶対 勝ち取ってこう
The running feelings, we will definitely win!
Yes!
共に二人競い合った 風の中でも
Even in the wind where we competed together
大きな背中追いかけてた 雨の中でも
Even in the rain where I chased your big back
何百 何千回と 積み重ねてきた
Hundreds, thousands of times, we have built this up
だから どこまでも 遠く
So, endlessly far
どこまでも 高く
Endlessly high
誰よりも 早く
Faster than anyone
誰よりも 強く
Stronger than anyone
さあ、今！
Now, at this moment!
駆け出した思いは もう止まらない
The running feelings can no longer be stopped
誰にも渡せない ゴールまで
I won't hand it over to anyone, until the goal!
弱気な気持ち 蹴飛ばして 何度だってずっと
Kicking away weak feelings, again and again, always
立ち上がって 走り抜け
Stand up and run through!
鳴り出した鼓動は 収まらない
The beating heart won't settle down
最後まで 全身全霊をかけて
To the very end, with all my heart and soul
両手を伸ばして
Reach out both hands
限界最高 超えていく
Go beyond the ultimate limit
伝説を追い越して
Overtake the legend
勝利へ！
To victory!
共に二人競い合った あの喜びも
That joy we competed for together
大きな背中追いかけてた あの憧れも
That admiration, chasing your big back
何千 何万回 生まれ変わっても
Even if we are reborn thousands, millions of times
何度も！何度も！走り続けるよ！
Again and again! Again and again! We will keep on running!
駆け出した思いは もう止まらない
The running feelings can no longer be stopped
(fight on!!) 挑みたい
(fight on!!) I want to challenge
(fight on!!) 掴みたい
(fight on!!) I want to grasp it
(fight on!!) 刻みたい
(fight on!!) I want to carve it
(fight on!!) 伝えたい
(fight on!!) I want to convey it
革命の火蓋切って保存
Cutting the fuse of revolution
伝説の旗掲げてゆこう
Raising the flag of legend, let's go
さぁ
Come on
legend-changer の中に飛び込んで
Legend-changer, jump into it
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
Become the party causing the enthusiasm
legend-changer 大胆に行こうぜ
Legend-changer, let's go boldly
本能醒ませ
Wake up instincts
感動起こせ保存
Awaken excitement
伝説刻んで
Carve out the legend
大地蹴って 蹴って 蹴って break!!
Kick the earth, kick, kick, kick, break!!
長い長い 夢の旅路を
This long, long dream journey,
一歩 また一歩と 確実に進んでいく
step by step, we surely move forward.
鋭い眼差しで見据える先に
Where I look with a sharp gaze,
みんなの笑顔があると信じて
believing everyone's smiles are there,
さあ行くよ！ 高く！
now let's go! High!
無双の強者(あいつ)に見る栄光を
The glory seen in that peerless powerhouse,
憧れにして終わらせるな
don't let it end as just an aspiration.
託された夢が先を切って
The entrusted dream takes the lead,
今 私たちの時代へと 変わっていく
now, changing into our era!
さぁ
Come on,
legend-changer の中に飛び込んで
Legend-changer, jump into it
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
Become the party causing the enthusiasm
legend-changer 大胆に行こうぜ保存
Legend-changer, let's go boldly
本能醒ませ
Wake up instincts
感動起こせ
Awaken excitement
伝説刻んで
Carve out the legend
大地蹴って 蹴って 蹴って break!!
Kick the earth, kick, kick, kick, break!!
(wo-o-o wo-o-o) break break break out!!
potatoになっていく
Becoming potatoes
もう救えない スクラブばかりのブルペンじゃ
In a bullpen full of nothing but irredeemable scrubs,
ちゃちな青春も お涙もそれすらないもんな保存
there's not even any cheap youth or tears to be found.
相当に笑えない コメディのワンシーンもままならない
It's not even funny, not even a single scene of this comedy.
冷めたチャウダーをただ混ぜ合わせた さもそんな人生さ
Just mixed up cold chowder, such is life.
掛け違えたボタンの身なりを
How long are you going to pretend not to see
いつのいつまで見ぬ振りしようか
your own ill-fitting appearance?
そうかい 抗弁のしようもないな
That's right, I can't even be bothered to argue back.
たまたま火事場に逃げ込んで 善かれと油を放り込んで
Accidentally escaped into the fire, and thinking I was helping, poured oil on it,
生活も計画も 全部がpotatoになっていく
my life and my plans are all turning into potatoes.
クイーンオブハート / 作詞・作曲：奏音69
[Title: Queen of Heart - Lyrics/Composition: Kanon69]
Welcome to the wonderland
ここでは誰もがマッド
Here, everyone is mad.
How are you doing, Miss?
狂ったお茶会(ティーパーティー)へようこそ
Welcome to the mad tea party.
どうせ足掻いても無駄
It's useless to struggle anyway.
死ぬまで帰れない
You can't go back until you die.
起き抜けのベッドが
The bed I just woke up from
黒の中で揺れる
glimmers inside the darkness.
こんなにも濡れているじゃないか
Isn't it so wet?
官能のバイオリン
The violin of sensuality...
響く声にそっと耳を立てて
gently listen to the echoing voice...
まるでアリスのように
just like Alice.
殺さぬように
Without killing you,
生かさぬように
without letting you live,
壊れるまで愛してあげる
I will love you until you break.
快楽は美薬なの
Pleasure is an aphrodisiac;
どんな刑もやがて
any punishment will soon
絹のように貼り付くわ
cling to you like silk.
This love is so insane
そう、これは夢の中
Yes, this is inside a dream.
女王(クイーン)の魔術(マジック)が解けていく
The Queen's magic is unraveling.
ごちそうさまでした、なんて
To say, "Thank you for the feast"...
安い仮面も擦り落ちそうで
Even the cheap mask seems about to slip off.
迷い込んだまま 戻る術もない
Still lost inside, with no way to return...
気づけば Only if I am dreaming
Before I knew it, only if I am dreaming.
Somebody wake me up!
追っ手は這う、そしてメアリアンは走り出す
The pursuers crawl, and Maryann starts to run,
帽子屋が待っているから、と歌う
singing, "Because the Hatter is waiting."
誰も見ない 嘘で嘘を塗り潰す時
When painting over lies with lies
嘘で嘘を塗り潰す時
that no one sees,
仮面の裏が見える
the back of the mask is revealed.
冒されたように
As if infected,
汚されたように
as if defiled,
地獄を咲かす花園
a flower garden blooming with hell.
秘密が欲しいなら
If you want secrets,
膝を突き地を舐めなさい
get on your knees and lick the ground.
お望みのまま 差し出した心臓を
The heart offered just as you wished...
Yes, Your Majesty
I can offer all my heart for you
殺さぬように
Without killing you,
生かさぬように
without letting you live,
この狂気のテラスさえ 味わうほど私は
the more I taste even this terrace of madness,
私は
I am...
The Queen of Heart
夢幻クライマックス / 作詞・作曲：大森靖子
[Title: Dream Climax - Lyrics/Composition: Oomori Seiko]
さよなら 甘い街
Goodbye, sweet city,
私をくれた人
the person who gave me myself,
遅れた人
the one who was left behind.
泣き癖、世話ない
My crying habit, no trouble...
理屈のない
Joy
喜び
without logic.
曖昧 未完成の
Ambiguous, incomplete...
過ち
I realized the mistake,
悟ったけど
but...
それは恋の季節
That is the season of love,
閃きは
the flash of light
戻らない
won't return.
シナリオ通りのカルマ
Karma according to the scenario
飛び越えてきた人生
A life that has leaped across
望み無くなって
Desires have vanished
愛だけ残ったの
And only love remained
それぞれの幸せ 振りかざしても
Even if we brandish our respective happiness
倒れない 二人で立っていようね自作の詞
Let's stand together, the two of us, without falling
艶やかでいてね
Please stay captivating
そのままでいてね
Please stay just the way you are
消えない幻
The phantom that won't fade away
無限クライマックス
Infinite Climax
最後の夜
The final night
エンドレスを刻め 斬新に
Carve an endless path in a novel way
抱きしめても 壊れないくらい
So strong that even if you embrace me, I wouldn't break
強くなりすぎたから
Because I became too strong
あなたにはわからない
You wouldn't understand
他から受ける からだの孤独
The body's loneliness received from others
それでも無神経に
Even so, insensitively,
季節が巡っていく
The seasons keep turning
いつも褒めてくれた 叱ってくれた
You always praised me, you scolded me
一人きりになると 寂しくなるね
When I am left alone, it gets lonely, doesn't it?
忘れないでいてね
Please don't forget me
憧れていてね
Please keep longing for me
綺麗な面影
The beautiful vestige
だから美しく 時を超えて
So, beautifully transcending time
同じ地球で 触れ合えるのは
The only thing we can touch on this same Earth
魂だけ そばに置いてね
Is our souls, so keep it by your side
強く生きていけるの
And I can live on strong
無限クライマックス
Infinite Climax
最後の夜
The final night
エンドレスを刻め 斬新に
Carve an endless path in a novel way
抱きしめても 壊れないくらい
So strong that even if you embrace me, I wouldn't break
強くなりすぎた
I became too strong
寂しい...
It's lonely...
だから美しく 時を超えて
So, beautifully transcending time
同じ地球で 触れ合えるのは
The only thing we can touch on this same Earth
魂だけ そばに置いてね
Is our souls, so keep it by your side
強く生きていこうね保存
Let's live on strong
はい。ということで...
Yes. So with that...
ゲストパートを見ていただきましたがいかがだったでしょうか？
we watched the guest part, but how did you like it?
いや本当にね、あの、ゲストの人とこういうことやりたいっていうのを...
No, really, wanting to do this kind of thing with the guests...
実現させていただきました。
was made a reality.
皆さん出演ありがとうございました。
Thank you everyone for appearing.
詳しくはですね、明日の振り返り配信でいろいろ裏話だったりをお話しさせていただこうと思いますので
For details, I'll be talking about behind-the-scenes stories in tomorrow's reflection stream,
ぜひ振り返り配信も来てください。そして！
so please definitely come to the reflection stream as well. And!
いかがですか？新衣装はいかがでしょうか？
How do you like it? How is my new outfit?
可愛いでしょう？
Isn't it cute?
たくさん差分があったんですけど気づきましたか？まあ、気づきますよね。
There were many variations, did you notice? Well, of course you did.
最初は、白い衣装から始まりまして
At first, it started with the white outfit,
そして「うまにゅーわーるど」ではですね、黒いパンツ姿であそこの階段から登場したんですけれども
and then for "Uma New World", I appeared from those stairs over there in a black pants outfit.
最初、みんな「あれ？ルイどこ？」みたいな感じになってて面白かったんですけれども
At first, it was funny how everyone was like, "Huh? Where is Lui?"
なんかね、ウマ娘を知ってる人は「まああそこから来るんやろうな」ってなんか
But somehow, people who know Uma Musume probably thought, "Well, she'll come from over there,"
後方腕組みしてたのがまた面白かったですね。はい。
and were crossing their arms in the back, which was also funny. Yes.
えー、メン限、この後ですね、21時20分から、メン限で撮影会もございますので
Also, after this, from 21:20, we will have a members-only photoshoot,
そちらもぜひいろんな差分を見せていきたいなと思いますので
where I want to show you various variations as well,
撮影会もぜひ来ていただけたら嬉しいでございます。
so I would be happy if you came to the photoshoot.
はい。えー重大発表はですね、このあと2曲あるんですけど
Yes. As for the major announcement, we have two more songs left,
今から歌う曲の後で発表させていただきますので
but we will announce it after the song I'm going to sing now,
ぜひ皆さん、ちょっと心待ちにしていただけたらなと思います。
so please look forward to it, everyone.
はい。じゃあ次の曲はですね、鷹嶺ルイ・セカンドアルバム「ラピスラズリ」から1曲歌わせていただきます。
Yes. Now, for the next song, I will sing a song from Takane Lui's second album, "Lapis Lazuli".
「抗う君へのレクイエム」です。お願いします。
"Requiem for the Resisting You". Here we go.
抗う君への鎮魂歌
[Title: Requiem for the Resisting You]
正しさだけが纏える術があれば
If there were a way to wear only righteousness,
少しは救われるだろうか
would I be saved a little?
その瞳へと問いかける
I ask that into those eyes.
守るべきを捨てるべきと誰に騙かされても
Even if someone misleads me on what to protect or discard,
もう心通わないなら
if our hearts no longer connect,
それは虚偽だ
then that is a falsehood.
何も捨てずに抗え
Resist without discarding anything.
力なき身じゃ
As someone powerless,
その覚悟が奇跡を創り
that resolve will create a miracle,
ただしさは伴わない
but righteousness will not accompany us.
失えば失うほどにさらに気高く
The more you lose, the more noble you become.
その意思で世界を怨め
With that will, resent the world.
心が軋んで何度も引き裂かれようとも
Even if my heart creaks and is torn apart many times,
抗え
resist.
かよわき一人を守り抜くための
To protect that one frail person,
この手のひらがどれだけ汚れてしまっても
no matter how dirty these palms of mine become,
構わないさ
I do not care,
君が笑うなら
if you smile,
僕は何にでもなる
I will become anything.
浅ましき期待 悦に浸るだけなら
If it is only to indulge in miserable expectations and pleasure,
人も獣も何一つ変わらない
both humans and beasts are not different at all.
鎖に似た自由を嘆いては保存
Mourning over a freedom that resembles chains,
歪に愛を求めているのでしょう
you must be seeking love in a distorted way.
どうか君だけは
Please, at least you,
僕を覚えていてほしい
I want you to remember me.
さあ 還らせ 君を
Come, let me return you
自由へと誘う
as I lead you to freedom.
俯けば俯くほどにさらに気高く
The more you look down, the more noble you become.
その意思で世界を揺らせ
With that will, shake the world.
心が軋んで何もかもが崩れても
Even if your heart creaks and everything crumbles,
抗え
resist.
かよわき一人を守り抜くための
To protect that one frail person,
この手のひらがどれだけ汚れてしまっても
no matter how dirty these palms of mine become,
構わないさ
I do not care,
君が笑うなら
if you smile,
壊して見せる この牢獄から
I will break you free from this prison.
君が笑えたとき
When you are able to smile,
僕は報われるのだろう
I will be saved.
消えかけた夢に
[Text: In a fading dream,]
バカにされても ボロボロだけど
[Text: even if ridiculed, though in tatters...]
Tori To Re:TreaT
[Text: Tori To Re:TreaT]
ZIGZAG
[Text: ZIGZAG]
[Text: 2026]
12.16
[Text: 12.16]
不安も、否定も、葛藤も。
[Text: Anxiety, denial, and conflict.]
私が歌で「反逆」する。
[Text: I will "rebel" through my song.]
1st Live 開催決定
[Text: 1st Live Decided to be held]
venue Kanadevia Hall
[Text: Venue: Kanadevia Hall]
REBELiON Takane Lui 1st Live
[Text: REBELiON Takane Lui 1st Live]
ここから始まる、私だけの物語。
[Text: My story begins here.]
はい、ということで！
Alright, so!
私、鷹嶺ルイの初めてのソロライブが決定しました！
My first solo live concert, Takane Lui 1st Live, has been officially decided!
イェーイ！フゥー！
Yay! Woo!
日程は半年後になる、なるのですが
The date is in half a year, but...
半年後の2026年12月16日水曜日となっております！
It will be on Wednesday, December 16th, 2026!
会場は、カナデビアホールです！
The venue is Kanadevia Hall!
もうね、4月の末にホロックスライブがありまして。
You know, we had the holoX Live at the end of April...
そして9月にねポックスがありまして。
And then we have Nepox in September.
そして12月に、鷹嶺ルイのソロライブがあるということで、
And then in December, Takane Lui's solo live will take place...
1年ね、2026年はすごい楽しめる年なんじゃないですか、ルイ友さん？
...making 2026 a year you can really enjoy, right, Luimoto-san?
はい。ということで、ルイ友さんにはね、色々お話ししたことがあると思うんですけれども、
Yes. So, I believe I've already shared various thoughts with my Luimotos, but...
私は前々からですね、今まで音楽活動を...
...for a long time, looking at my music activities so far...
...で道を作ってきてくれた先輩、そら先輩だったり、
...and the seniors who paved the way for us, like Sora-senpai,
すいちゃん、あずちゃん、そしてわため、そしてカリ先輩のようにですね、
Sui-chan, Azu-chan, Watame, and Calli-senpai,
ファーストライブから少しずつ、段階、階段を上がっていって、
climbing up the stairs step by step, starting from the 1st live,
広い会場でソロライブをするという、そんな物語に憧れていました。
and performing a solo live at a huge venue. I've always admired that story.
だから、もし私がライブをやることになった際には、
So, if I ever got the chance to do a live concert,
ファースト、セカンド、サード、フォースと、
I wanted to go from 1st, 2nd, 3rd, and 4th...
順々に会場を大きくして、ゆくゆくはアリーナという夢を叶えたい、
...gradually increasing the size of the venue, and eventually fulfill my dream of an arena.
はい、そう思っていて、
Yes, that's what I thought,
ルイ友さんにはね、常々お伝えをしていたと思います。
and I think I have always told my Luimotos about it.
そのためにね、定期的なソロライブができる活動、頑張りたいなと思って今まで努力を、え、してきました。
That's why I've put in the effort so far, wishing to do activities where I can perform solo lives regularly.
そして、これからもします。
And I will continue to do so.
最近のホロライブはですね、結構、より多くの方が入る会場での開催が多くて、
Lately, Hololive concerts are often held in venues that can hold a lot of people,
私の夢はちょっと難しいのかなとは、思っていたんですけれども、
so I thought my dream might be a little difficult to achieve.
こうやって私の夢を理解してくださり、叶えて、叶えるべく、
But they understood my dream, and to make it come true...
まずは私の希望だったカナデビアホールにてファーストライブをやらせていただくことになりました！
...first, I will be holding my 1st Live at my desired venue, Kanadevia Hall!
おめでとう、ありがとう！そして、あのトレンドもありがとうございます。
Congratulations! Thank you! And thank you so much for getting me on the trending list.
ここからが、鷹嶺ルイの新章の、え、新章の物語の始まりでございます。
From here, the new chapter of Takane Lui's story begins.
まずはファーストライブをね、開催してから次を考えるべきだとは思うんですけれども、
Though I should probably focus on holding the 1st live first before thinking about the next step,
私はセカンド、サード、フォース、その先のライブへのビジョンまで考えております。
I am already looking at the vision for the 2nd, 3rd, 4th, and the lives beyond.
はい。今回の生誕ライブのタイトルでもあるように、
Yes, just like the title of today's birthday concert...
「Luminous Stairs」、輝かしい階段を駆け上がるために、
...'Luminous Stairs,' in order to climb up these radiant stairs...
そして、一緒にこの物語を紡いでいくために、
...and to weave this story together with you...
少しでも行きたいなと思ってくださった方は、
If any of you want to come even just a little,
え、次にね、繋げるために応募したり、ライブを見てくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be glad if you apply or watch the live to help us connect to the next step.
ライブのタイトルは、「REBELLION」になっております。はい、レベリオンです。
The title of the concert is "REBELLION." Yes, Rebellion.
はい、反逆という意味でございます。
Yes, it means "rebellion."
私がいつも抱えてる不安や、そして色々な否定の声、
The anxieties I always carry, the various negative voices...
そして私自身の葛藤、
...and my own struggles...
これからも私はそれを私の歌で反逆していきたい、そんな気持ちで込めさせていただきました。
I want to rebel against them with my songs, which is the message I put into the title.
最高のライブになるようにたくさん準備をしていますので、ぜひ楽しみに待っていてください。
I'm preparing a lot to make it the best concert ever, so please look forward to it!
はい。ここからまた新たに鷹嶺ルイの物語が始まるということで、
Since a brand new chapter of Takane Lui's story begins here,
アーティスト写真を作りました！こちらです。
we have created a new artist photo! Here it is.
はい、めちゃくちゃかっこいいですね。かっこかわいい。
Yes, it's so cool! Cool and cute.
はい。アーティスト活動の際にはこちら使っていこうかなと思っておりますので、
I'll be using this photo for my music activities,
よろしくお願いいたします。
so please look forward to it.
そして、ここまで、ファースト、セカンド、アコースティックとアルバムを作ってきましたが、
Up until now, I've released my 1st, 2nd, and acoustic albums,
今回ライブを盛り上げるために、4曲...
but to hype up this live show, we have 4 new songs...
...新しく作りまして、収録させていただいた、
...newly created and recorded in a mini-album,
ミニアルバムも、本日ライブ終了後に予約開始です！
which will be available for pre-order right after today's live ends!
ね、たくさん曲がありますね、鷹嶺ルイ。
Takane Lui has quite a lot of songs now, doesn't she?
はい。え、「The Legendary」というタイトルをつけさせていただきましたミニアルバムでございます。
Yes, this mini-album is titled "The Legendary."
この後にね、披露する新曲も入っております。
It also includes the new song that I'll perform later.
完全生産限定盤には全員にサインがつきます。
The Complete Limited Edition will come with an autograph for everyone.
はい、完全生産限定盤には全員に、え、直筆サインがつきますので、
Yes, the Complete Limited Edition features a handwritten autograph for every purchase,
日頃の感謝を込めてサインを書きますので、ぜひ予約してください。
I will sign each one with gratitude, so please pre-order it.
お求めやすい通常盤もあります。こちらはちょっとサインついてないんですけど、
There's also a more affordable regular edition, though it doesn't have an autograph.
通常盤もございますので、ぜひお手元に取っていただけますと嬉しいです。
We have a regular edition as well, so I'd be glad if you grab a copy.
今回のライブ、そして、この後に予約開始されるミニアルバムのハッシュタグは共通で、
The hashtag for both this concert and the mini-album starting pre-orders next is the same:
ハッシュタグ「#鷹嶺ルイの反逆」となっております。
it is "#鷹嶺ルイの反逆" (Takane Lui's Rebellion).
皆さん、たくさんポストして盛り上げてくださいね。
Everyone, please post a lot on social media and hype it up!
ビジュ良いっしょ？ビジュ良いよね。
The visual is great, right? It really looks good.
以上、ソロライブとミニアルバムの告知でした。
That's all for the solo live and mini-album announcements.
まだお知らせはございます！はい、お知らせと重大告知がございます。
But there are still more announcements! Yes, some news and a major announcement.
次はお待ちかねのグッズ紹介です！はい、こちら。
Next is the highly anticipated merch showcase! Here it is.
鷹嶺ルイ誕生日記念2026ということで、
For Takane Lui's Birthday Commemoration 2026...
キービジュアルはですね、今回お披露目させていただいた新衣装を着て、ケーキを食べている鷹嶺ルイです。
For the key visual, here's Takane Lui in her new outfit, eating cake.
久ののらり先生に写真を撮っていただきました。可愛いでしょ？それでは一つずつ見ていきましょう。
Norari Hisano-sensei drew this illustration. Cute, right? Let's check them out one by one!
はい、1つ目はこちら。アクリルジオラマスタンドになっております。キービジュアルを使用したアクリルジオラマになっております。
First up is this acrylic diorama stand, which features the key visual design.
ルイ友さんとですね、がんもも可愛く執事風におめかしをしております。可愛い。ふふっ。
The Luitomos and Ganmo are also dressed up nicely in butler outfits. So cute!
はい、続いてはこちら。新衣装にね、こちら。新衣装の、はい、こちらとかについている...
Next is this. It's based on the emblems featured on the new outfit...
2種類のエムブレムをモチーフにしたピンバッジでございます。
These are pin badges based on two types of emblems.
いろんなところにつけて密かにルイ友アピールをしてください。おしゃれでしょ？
Put them on your things to subtly show you're a Luitomo. Very stylish!
続いてはこちら。はい。新衣装をモチーフにしたポーチになってます。おしゃれ。
Moving on, here is a pouch modeled after the new outfit. So chic!
裏面はですね、メッシュポケットになっているので、缶バッジはもちろん、今回一緒に販売するピンバッジもつけやすいデザインになっております。
The back has a mesh pocket, making it easy to attach can badges and the new pin badges.
最後は、これ欲しかったんじゃないかな？こちら。はい、新衣装のショートパンツバージョンの...
Lastly, I bet you really wanted this! Here is the new outfit's short pants version...
ほろふれと同じくらいのサイズのぬいぐるみです。可愛い。ぜひこの機会にお迎えいただけたら嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
It's a plushie about the same size as the Holo-Friends series. Cute! Please take this chance to get one.
フルセット購入特典はこちら。ポストカードになっておりまして、数量限定版と通常版がございます。
Here is the full set purchase bonus postcard. It comes in limited-quantity and regular editions.
数量限定版は、えー、直筆サインがつきます。たくさん用意しておるので、ま、ゆっくり、ゆっくり選んでください。
The limited edition includes a handwritten signature. There's plenty of stock, so take your time!
販売時間はですね、少し余裕を持たせて21時15分からカートオープンです。はい、以上、グッズ紹介でした。
Sales will open slightly later at 21:15. That concludes the merchandise introduction!
そして、もう一つ重大告知です。こちら。なんと、私が夢見ていました...
And now, another major announcement. This is something I've dreamed of...
BAYFMさんにてレギュラーラジオの番組が決定しました！
My own regular radio show on BAYFM has been greenlit!
放送日はですね、毎週金曜日24時30分から24時57分。初回放送日は7月3日金曜日となっております。
It will air every Friday from 24:30 to 24:57. The first broadcast is on Friday, July 3rd!
Xでも初回配信分のお便りを募集するので、メールアドレスも公開しますので、Xのフォローをよろしくお願いいたします。楽しみにしててね。
I'll accept letters on X and post the mail address there, so please follow my X account!
はい、次の曲が最後の曲になります。先ほども紹介させていただきました新曲になっておりまして、名前は「Soar」と言います。
Now, the next song will be the last one. It's the new song I introduced earlier, titled "Soar."
ソロライブでもみんなと一緒に歌いたいなと思って、みんなが声出しできる新曲を作ってきました。
I wanted to sing with everyone at my solo concert, so I made this song for you to sing along.
ナナホシさんに書き下ろしていただいた爽やかな楽曲になっております。
It's a refreshing tune written specifically for me by Nanahoshi-san.
このあと21時から、ちょっと過ぎかも知れないけど、ミュージックビデオのプレミア公開もあります。
The music video premiere is coming up tonight starting around 21:00.
楽曲は本日24時にリリースです。この曲は、コーラスはホロメンが歌ってくれております。ライブまでにたくさん聴いて覚えてくれたら嬉しいです。
The digital track releases at midnight! The chorus features other Hololive members, so please learn it!
では、早速聴いていただきましょう。皆さん一緒に歌いたい曲、Soarです。どうぞ。
Now, let's get right to it. Here is "Soar," a song I want to sing with all of you.
何度でも君を呼んで、また歩いてゆく
I will call your name over and over as I keep walking forward.
Soar
一歩踏み出したらもう未来さ
Take just one step forward, and it's already the future.
昨日つまずいた道も、今日からは近道だ
Even the road I stumbled on yesterday is now a shortcut.
息をするたびに広がる景色
The scenery broadens with every breath I take.
私を信じていいと言って
Tell me that it's okay to believe in myself.
つぶやきも希望になって
Even my whispers turn into hope,
あふれては声になって
overflowing and becoming a voice.
何度目を閉じても消せないな
No matter how many times I close my eyes, I can't erase it.
高く飛べるよ　そうだろう　抑えられない
I can fly high, right? I can't suppress it.
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one gives me permission to spread my wings...
もう決めたよ　迷わない
My mind is made up; I won't hesitate anymore.
向かい風もきっと進んでる証拠だって
Even a headwind is proof that I'm moving forward,
君に伝えるんだ
and that's what I want to tell you.
どんな重力も心までは
No gravity can bind my heart,
縛れない　曲げられない
it cannot be bound, it cannot be bent.
この手で確かめたい
I want to feel it for myself with these hands.
胸焦がした思いで
With this yearning in my heart,
爪痕をさあ刻んで
I'll leave my mark.
嵐の空模様切り裂いて
Cutting through the stormy skies!
もっと輝くよ そうだろう
We will shine brighter, right?
叫べばいい
Just scream it out!
憧れより眩しい歌 そして激しい歌
A song more dazzling than longing, and an intense song.
いつか耳を塞いだ
The hands that once blocked my ears...
その両手がきっと翼になる
...will surely become wings.
そう思うんだ
That's what I believe.
ゆずれない衝動
This unyielding impulse.
高く飛べるよ そうだろう
We can fly high, right?
抑えられない
It cannot be held back.
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one grants permission for me to spread my wings,
もう決めたよ 迷わない
I've decided, I won't hesitate anymore.
向かい風もきっと進んでる証拠だって
Even the headwind is surely proof that I'm moving forward...
君に伝えるんだ
...that is what I'll convey to you.
何度でも君を呼んで また歩いてゆく
Calling your name over and over, I'll walk once again.
皆さん本日生誕祭に来てくださってありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to my birthday celebration today!
ソロライブ楽しみにしててね！
Please look forward to my solo concert!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ルイ友へ♡
[Letter: To Louis-tomo ♡]
みんなの応援のおかげで……ついに私もソロライブできるよ！！本当にありがとう♡
[Letter: Thanks to everyone's support... I can finally hold my solo concert!! Thank you so much ♡]
もっともっと努力して光り輝く階段をのぼって、いろんな景色をみせてね ➔ 任せろー！
[Letter: I'll work harder to climb the shining stairs... 'Show me all kinds of scenery' ➔ 'Leave it to us!']
私の物語には君が必要です！！これからもよろしくね！！ るい 2026.06.11
[Letter: You are indispensable to my story!! Please look after me from now on as well!! - Rui, 2026.06.11]